Pierre Eugène du Simitière collection LCP.DuSimitiere
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series VII. Original Journals and Extracts, [1411.Q] (Box 5)
  - "Indian Betty's Petition," by Nicholas Skull, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Liberty," by and in the handwriting of the Reverend Thomas Hopkinson, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series VIII. Papers relating to New England and New York, circa 1774; [1412.Q] (Volume 3)
  The series “Papers relating to New England, New York, etc.,” contains materials Du Simitière gathered and copied for a history of New York. The materials are mostly written and drawn by Du Simitière and they are gathered in a bound volume with an index on the first few pages. The material includes tombstone engravings, burial records, chronologies, death and marriage records, and Du Simitière’s sketches, including a sketch of the New York state house. There are also various newspaper clippings throughout the volume. The volume contains some notes on Pennsylvania, New Jersey and New England. The materials are recorded in Italian and English and were probably compiled around 1774.
- Series IX. Papers relating to Pennsylvania, New England, Etc., circa 1780; [1413] (Volume 4)
  The series “Papers relating to Pennsylvania and New England” contains information gathered by Du Simitière about the history and current state of affairs in Pennsylvania and New England. The volume includes a table of contents and an index. Of special interest are the several bibliographies of the books available to Du Simitière about the colonies, Native Americans, Pennsylvania, the West Indies, and New England. Other documents include chronologies, catalogs, copies of historical documents, newspaper clippings, and lists of families with chariots and coaches in Pennsylvania in 1782. The material in this series was probably compiled during the 1780s, Documents are in English.
- Series X. Miscellaneous papers from du Simitière (Scraps), 1740-1783 (Box 6)
  The series “Miscellaneous papers from Du Simitière (Scraps)” consists of three boxes containing a variety of materials that pertain to numerous topics, some of which are covered in other series. Many of the documents are copies of original documents done by Du Simitière. The collection includes drawings, journals, poems, newspaper clippings, vocabularies, and notes on North American Indians. The order created by the first survey was maintained, and the series appears to be arranged by topic. The series dates from 1740 to 1783 with the exception of ten medieval Latin manuscripts. The collection is written in Latin, French, Chinese, and English. This series contains some material relating specifically to Philadelphia.
  Researchers who have not located a document or topic they are seeking elsewhere in the collection should browse this series.
  - "A Catalogue of Newspapers and Pamphlets bought at Du Simitière's Auction", undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Roman medal list by du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Society of Cincinnati, June 18, 1783, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Return of the Philadelphia Troop of Light Horse," May 3, 1782, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Latin manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Latin prayers in Gothic script, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Latin manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Latin prayers from printed prayer book, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Latin manuscript, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Latin sermons from prayer book titled Decimus Sermo and Undecimus Sermo, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Calendar leaflet, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Medieval Latin prayers to the Blessed Virgin, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Medieval Latin prayer book, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "On the lately discovered Wild Raspberries," by [Breintnall, Joseph?], 1740 July (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Pencil sketch of architectural ornamentation, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Cardboard cover bearing inscription "Quebec and Nova-Scotia./ No 15/.", undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Lievre River Journey map made by unknown traveler, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Quebec history extracts from Douglas's British Settlements in North America and Peter Kalm's Travels into North America, 1770, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Preservation of leaves, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Notes on De Buffon's L'Histoire Naturelle, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Latin epigram with English translation, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Copy of the Log of a voyage from the West Indies to the Delaware River and Bay, then the New York Coast, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Du Simitière's notes on Quebec, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - List of "Unknown animals from van der Donck's natural history book", undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Caterpillars in the Carolinas, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - List of Quadrupeds found in du Simitière's Synopsis of North American Animals, 1759, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Early history of Quebec, 1659-1766, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Description of goldenrod, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Metamorphosis of a black caterpillar, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Inventory of old coins, 1767-1769, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - List of leaves sent to Peter Colinson for impressions, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - "Liste de Couleurs," by du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Bibliography of articles in Monthly Review and London Magazine regarding Nova Scotia, 1748-1755, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous references to Canada and Nova Scotia, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Extract of a letter from London" concerning petitions presented by Benjamin Franklin to the King, 1766 November 30, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - List of old engravings and curiosa in the possession of du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Ancient coins and medals in du Simitière's collection, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - List of coins and medals belonging to du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Anonymous author's love poem, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - "Deism," attributed to Phillis Wheatley, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - "Opera avec Jeannot et Theresse," by unknown author, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "On the Death of Mr. Snider Murder'd by Richardson," by "Phillis", attributed to Phillis Wheatley, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - List of botanical specimens in du Simitière's possession, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Philosophical poem, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - "Epitaph" about Katherine Grary, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Plan of city in Java or Sumatra by du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - "Musing near a Cool Spring," poem about Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - List of botanical specimens sent to du Simitière, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - "Le Tamarin", undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - "Letters from an American Farmer" note, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Note from Lieutenant John Smith to General Israel Putman, 1776 December (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - List of coins, 1737, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Lists from Santo Domingo, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - "The Wonderful Prophet," by an unknown author (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - "Sonnet," from Gentleman's Magazine, 1740 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Verso-Scurrilous six-line doggerel, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - "T'was in the pleasant month of May", undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Anonymous author's love poem, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - "On the Present Situation of affairs in America," March 10, 1775, 1775 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - "Scots Song upon America", undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Letter to Du Simitière by an unidentified author, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - "Histoire du donneur d'Eau benit", undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Note from John Stewart to Harrison Gray, 1768 April 23 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - "Table des chapitres de la Chrysologie contenue dans un Manuscrit ecrit preparent de 216 pages d'en grand papier de compite", undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Draft of a letter to Jean-Babtiste Iseard de Lisle de Sales, undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Memorial to Christopher Columbus, undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - "Les Proverbes de Salomon" exert from Old Testament, undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Religious treatise dealing in Catholic theology, undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Natural history book dealing with monstrosities nature has produced in the human race, quadrupeds, bipeds, etc., 1775 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - References on a pamphlet about Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Title page with inscription, undated (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Chinese manuscript, undated (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Chinese manuscript on pink rice paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Calligraphy chart, undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Colors of the English colonies chart, undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - List of travel books, undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Newspaper items describing the auction of mineral specimens, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Books on the natural history of North America quoted by de Bufon and a list of small animals, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Copied newspaper items relating to the sale of Sir Ashton Lever's Holophusicon, 1781-1782 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Account of the public sale of John Bessnet's goods, undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Resolution clearing John Peters of Philadelphia, PA, undated (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Extracts of the minutes of the Committee of Inspection and Observation regarding William Sitgreaves and Peter Ozeas, undated (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Examination of Jabez Fisher in regard to his publication of several articles against the Committee of Inhabitants of Philadelphia, 1775 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Patriotic poem condemning George III, undated (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Letter from Chaddsford, PA describing the battle of the Brandywine, 1777 September 11 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - "To Mr. John Beveridge A.M. Professor of the Latin Language in the College and Academy of Philadelphia" satire letter, undated (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Resolutions adopted by merchants and traders in Philadelphia boycotting certain British products, 1769 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Historical account of the University of Pennsylvania, undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Historical account of the American Philosophical Society, undated (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - List of Philadelphia and Pennsylvania industries, buildings, etc., undated (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - "The Reverend Mr. Spin-Shaile", undated (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Resolutions of the Committee of Safety in Philadelphia, PA, 1775 July 10 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Resolutions adopted by merchants and traders in Philadelphia boycotting certain British products, 1769 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - List of Philadelphia curiosities, undated (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Resolutions of the Committee of Safety in Philadelphia, PA, 1779 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Copy of Howe's Proclamation to the Citizen's of Pennsylvania, August 27, 1777, undated (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - The Original State of Thirty Baptist Churches whose Messengers Annually Meet in Association at Philadelphia, undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - "Inscription, On a Curious Chamber Stove in the Form of an Urn contriv'd in such a Manner as to make the Flame descend instead of rising from the Fire: Invented by the celebrated Benjamin Franklin", undated (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Bond of John Spark, 1779 July 15 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Poem on Tammany, the Indian chief, undated (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - "Letter from Hodder Verling to James Hamilton, Philadelphia, PA", 1763 January 27 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Call for volunteers "to drive our inhuman enemy to destruction", 1777 July 12 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Copy of General George Washington's military orders, December 25, 1776, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - East New Jersey land recovery suits, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Letter from W[illiam] Sitgreaves to Committee of Inspection and Observation, Philadelphia, PA, 1776 April 2 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Boarder lines of Ornaments broadside regarding the death of Monsieur Stephen Regne, 1783 October 17 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Sales of proprietarie's lands and of negro prisoners newspaper clippings, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Cardboard cover bearing inscription "New Netherlands New York No. 20", undated (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Extracts of epitaphs of Governor Bradstreet, Captain Humphrey Atherton, and Richard Mather, undated (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - List of Objects for drawing, undated (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Hickory and Calaba trees descriptions, undated (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Cardboard cover bearing inscription "New-England Boston No. 18", undated (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Caricature showing two men in a cart, a man on a horse, and a grotesque mask, undated (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Description of antiquities of Reverend Ezra Stiles, undated (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Sketches showing four facades of various buildings [Harvard?], undated (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Description of drawing entitled "An east View of Ridge of Rocks forming the West Side of Beach in Rhode Island", undated (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Brief notes extracted from a book about New York towns, undated (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Copy of Cherokee-South Carolina Treaty, December 18, 1761, undated (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Copy of letter from Fred Winter regarding Fort Moore in Carolina and Fort Augusta in Georgia, April 5, 1764, undated (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Information regarding South Carolina, undated (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - "Ode on the King's birth day June 4th, 1776, Sung by some gentlemen of the English army prisoners at Burlington", undated (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - List of English colonies and rivers with their names in the Iroquois language, undated (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Ink impression of an unidentified leaf, undated (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - References to early settlements in New York and Illinois, undated (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - List of charters of Massachusetts and Georgia, undated (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Account of Adam Poe's Indian encounter, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - List of books and page numbers referencing Indian hieroglyphics, maps, origins, drunkenness, etc., undated (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Titles of articles about Indian missions, undated (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Booklet containing English words with their Shawnee counterpart, undated (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Booklet containing English words with their Shawnee counterpart, compiled by Colonel R. Butler, February 16, 1782, undated (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Notes on Indian language, undated (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Notes on Seneca Indians and Sullivan's Expedition, 1779, undated (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Extract of Chickasaw vocabulary from Adair's History of the American Indian, 1624, undated (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - List of Royal patents issued by various royalty, explorers, and navigators, undated (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Page numbers of Adair's works about American Indians, undated (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Manuscript notes for a letter to M. Count de Gebelin on the Indian bible of John Elliot, undated (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Draft of du Simitière's letter to Jean-Baptiste Isoard de Lisle de Sales, undated (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Chart describing the method of trading used by Northern Indians, undated (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - Extracts from various journals concerning Indian customs, undated (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Excerpt of Indian to English dictionary from Dictionary and Etymologie de la langue latine, undated (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - List of Indian antiquities and references of works about Indian antiquities, undated (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Bibliography and brief essay about the Iroquois language and trader, undated (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - List of books and page numbers for references on Indian life, undated (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Books and page numbers of accounts of Indian life, undated (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - List of magazine articles on Indians, 1757-1758, undated (Box 8, Folder 149)
  - List of topics found in Jonathan Carver's Travels through the interior Parts of North America, in the Years 1756, 7 and 8," 1781, undated (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - Extract of the Lord's Prayer in Mohican taken from a work by Lawrence Claesse, 1715, undated (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Paper cover bearing inscription "Acts of Parliament/and other Parliamentary Papers/ of the years 1774 and following", undated (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding London and New York, 1773 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding the destruction of tea on the brig Fortune, 1774 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding Great Britain's quarrel with her colonies, undated (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Newspaper clipping "Remarks on Dr. Franklin and his Political Conduct", 1775 September (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Newspaper clipping from a London paper regarding oppression in the colonies, 1774 May 1 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Newspaper clipping "Address to the Soldiers", 1775 March (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Newspaper clipping about economic and social conditions in the world titled "Universal Catechism", undated (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Newspaper clipping with Hartley's plan for conciliating America, 1775 December (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding the interception of letters by Boston faction, 1773 September 4 (Box 8, Folder 170)
- Series XI. Papers relating to New York Politics, 1768-1771; [396.F] (Box 9)
  The series ”Papers relating to New York politics, 1768-1771” predominately deals with the suspension of the New York House of Assembly by Governor Moore, the elections of the next New York House of Assembly, and the political factions involved in these elections. This series primarily contains newspaper clippings from New York newspapers such as Parker’s New-York Gazette, the Weekly Post-Boy, the Weekly Mercury, the New-York Gazette, and the Weekly Post, but there are occasionally newspaper clippings from other colonial newspapers, particularly from Boston and New Jersey. These newspaper clippings are mostly letters addressed to the printers or to the “Freeholders and Freemen of New York.” Individuals discussed in the letters include the leaders of opposing parties of the New York House of Assembly, Philip Livingston and James Delancey; and Sons of Liberty leaders, Isaac Sears and Alexander McDougall. Additional topics of the newspaper clippings and other documents include the abolishment of the Committee of Safety, the Quartering Act, and the Townshend Acts; and the Battle of Golden Hill. Documents of interest in this series are the minutes of the Common Council of New York on November 19, 1768, a document containing a song “The American Whig’s Address to the Dissenters;” speeches from meetings of the Sons of Liberty; correspondence regarding the Committee of Safety; and the votes tally for the election of the New York House of Assembly in which Philip Livingston won on February 10, 1768. There is also a signed petition regarding the non-importation agreement and a copy of a letter that was hung in a coffee house and addressed to three merchants. The writers of the letter inquired whether certain merchants planned on importing goods, and is signed by “The Mohocks,” a name derived from an eighteenth century London Gang.
  This series dates from February 8, 1768 to October 1, 1770. The documents are mostly arranged in chronological order. Their quantity and arrangement make them an excellent starting point for anyone studying this period of New York politics. All the materials are in English.
  - Papers [wanting] in my collection of New York Politics from 1768-1771, undated (Box 9, Folder (I).1)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding New York, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (I).13-24)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding New York, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (I).25-28)
  - Newspaper clipping: "A Young Tory to the Freeholders and Freemen", 1768 March 5 (Box 9, Folder (I).33)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding New York, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (I).34-37)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding New York, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (I).39-42)
  - Minutes of the Common Council in the City of New York, 1762 November 19 (Box 9, Folder (I).43)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding New York, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (I).44-50)
  - Song: "The American Whig's Address to the Dissenters", undated (Box 9, Folder (II).1)
  - Newspaper clipping: From one Freeman to the Freeman and Freeholders of the City of New York, 1769 January 9 (Box 9, Folder (II).26)
  - Newspaper clippings: To the Freeholders and Freemen of the City of New York, 1769 (Box 9, Folder (II).28-30)
  - Speech and newspaper clippings, 1769 (Box 9, Folder (II).34-36)
  - Newspaper clipping: To the Freeholders and Freemen of the City and County of New York, undated (Box 9, Folder (II).43)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (II).52)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1769 February 6 (Box 9, Folder (II).57)
  - Meeting minutes of Sons of Liberty, 1769 April 11 (Box 9, Folder (II).59)
  - Address, undated (Box 9, Folder (II).60)
  - "To the Commericial Committee of Inspection for Importation of English Goods", undated (Box 9, Folder (II).61)
  - Newspaper article regarding the Society of Dissenters, 1769 July (Box 9, Folder (II).62-67)
  - Newspaper article regarding the Society of Dissenters, 1769 July 25 (Box 9, Folder (II).68.72)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Simeon Cooley and non-importation agreement, 1769 July 24 (Box 9, Folder (II).74)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding the Despotic Assembly, 1769 November 13 (Box 9, Folder (II).76)
  - Correspondence from Freemen and Freeholders, 1769 December 16 (Box 9, Folder (II).82)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding Freeholders and Freemen, 1769 December 20 (Box 9, Folder (II).86-91)
  - New York Province House Assembly votes tally, 1768 (Box 9, Folder (III).1)
  - Proclamation by "Pluto", undated (Box 9, Folder (III).1.5)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding the House of Representatives of New York, 1769 December 22 (Box 9, Folder (III).2.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1769 December 29 (Box 9, Folder (III).4)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1769 December 12 (Box 9, Folder (III).7-15)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 January (Box 9, Folder (III).15.5-19)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 January 15 (Box 9, Folder (III).20-26)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).26.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 January 22 (Box 9, Folder (III).27)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).28)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding support of the troops, 1770 January 17 (Box 9, Folder (III).29-30)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding the disturbances between the inhabitants and the soldiers, 1770 January (Box 9, Folder (III).34-48)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 January 29 (Box 9, Folder (III).42)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Captain McDougall, 1770 March 5 (Box 9, Folder (III).45-46)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 March 14 (Box 9, Folder (III).48)
  - "Proclamation by John and Isaac, Lords of the Presbyterian Faction of New York and the Territories", 1770 March 25 (Box 9, Folder (III).51)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Captain McDougall, 1770 March 19 (Box 9, Folder (III).52)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Captain McDougall, 1770 March-April (Box 9, Folder (III).54-65)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 April (Box 9, Folder (III).66-69)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding advertisement, 1770 April 9 (Box 9, Folder (III).70)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Captain McDougall, 1770 April 9 (Box 9, Folder (III).72-74)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 April 9 (Box 9, Folder (III).76-77)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Captain McDougall, 1770 April 16 (Box 9, Folder (III).80-81)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding the importance, privileges and duty of grand juries, 1770 April 16 (Box 9, Folder (III).82-84)
  - Newspaper clipping regarding Lieutenant Governor Delancey, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).85-91)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 April 26-30 (Box 9, Folder (III).92-100)
  - Newspaper clipping by "Satiricust", undated (Box 9, Folder (III).101-104)